Guide to the Eliza Darling Hastings papers and memorabilia
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Eliza Darling Hastings papers and memorabilia
1912-1932
SC0588
Hastings, Eliza Darling.
1 Linear feet
Collection includes dance cards from Encina Club, Roble Club, Jolly-Up, and other Stanford dances, 1912-1916; invitations and calling cards; letters received from L. G. Weber, and fellow students Edmund W. Pugh and Ward Belnap Blodget, 1913-1915; Stanford songbooks; and assorted mementos, 1913-1932.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Eliza Darling earned her B.A. in graphic arts at Stanford University in 1916; in 1917 she married her classmate Harlow Harvey Amos Hastings, Jr.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes dance cards from Encina Club, Roble Club, Jolly-Up, and other Stanford dances, 1912-1916; invitations and calling cards; letters received from L. G. Weber, and fellow students Edmund W. Pugh and Ward Belnap Blodget, 1913-1915; Stanford songbooks; and assorted mementos, 1913-1932.
Access Terms
Blodget, Ward Belnap.; Hastings, Doug Darling; Hastings, Eliza Darling.; Pugh, Edmund W.; Dance cards.; Dance--Social aspects--United States.
Collection Contents
- Dance Cards
  - Encina Club at Home, Sept. 21, 1912; in honor of Nineteen Twelve Crew (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jolly-Up, Oct. 25, 1912 and Delta Chi, Nov. 27, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Delta Chi, Feb. 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Encina Club, Feb. 15, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - S. U. Military Band, Mar. 7, 1914; [dance] Apr. 11, 1913; and Roble Club, Apr. 25, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Encina Club, Nov. 15, 1913 and Sophomore Cotillion, Nov. 21, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Encina Club [1913] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Encina Club, Apr. 25, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1916 Jolly-Up, Sept. 18, 1914 and Encina Club, Sept. 26, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Band Dance, Oct. 2, 1914 and Gym Club Dance Oct. 30, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Encina Club, Nov. 21, 1914; Thanksgiving Dance, Nov. 28, 1914; and Firemen's Annual Ball [Ventura], Dec. 31, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Band Dance, Feb. 12, 1915 and Encina Club, Feb. 13, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beta Theta Pi, Feb. 27, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chi Omega Installation Banquet, Mar. 6, 1915 and [dance] Mar. 20, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Swimming Club Dance, Sept. 4, 1915 and Encina Club, Sept. 25, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Gym Club, Oct. 16, 1915 and Encina Club, Nov. 20, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sophomore Cotillion Nov. 24, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Encina Club, Feb. 12, 1916; Sigma Chi, Feb. 18, 1916; and [dance, 1916] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - La Liana, Mar. 25, 1916; Junior Prom, Mar. 31, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Delta Delta Delta, Mar. 10, 1916 and Kappa Kappa Gamma, Apr. 29, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Senior Ball, May 22, 1916 [2 booklets, one containing admission ticket for H. H. Hastings] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chi Omega, Feb. 9, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Stanford Band, Chi Omega, Roble, no date (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - San Francisco, Apr. 7, no year (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified dances, no date (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Invitations and Other Cards
  - Encina Club invitations (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Roble Club invitations (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fraternity invitations (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personal invitation cards (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Calling cards (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Place cards (Box 2, Folder 9)